<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Xuanrui Qi - career</title>
    <subtitle>PhD candidate in mathematics, Nagoya University</subtitle>
    <link href="https://www.xuanruiqi.com/tags/career/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://www.xuanruiqi.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.xuanruiqi.com/tags/career/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Looking for a job</title>
        <published>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.xuanruiqi.com/blog/job/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://www.xuanruiqi.com/blog/job/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am expecting my PhD in mathematics from Nagoya University by September 2025 (the date might vary, but I am expecting my degree by early 2026).
I plan to enter industry after graduation, with a tentative start date of &lt;strong&gt;October 2025&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (this date is pretty solid, and I am willing to start
working by then regardless of whether I finish my defense).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;positions-i-am-looking-for&quot;&gt;Positions I am looking for&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking for &lt;strong&gt;engineering and&#x2F;or research positions in software and tech&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and I am &lt;strong&gt;open to all kinds of work&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, my expertise are in the following fields:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functional programming (particularly OCaml&#x2F;Haskell);&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language design;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language runtimes &amp;amp; implementation;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;formal methods and verification;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blockchain technology;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(to some extent) security.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have a solid background in mathematics and computer science in general, and am open to almost any kind of work, especially areas
that require mathematical knowledge, such as optimization, algorithm design and data science.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an opening for a job that requires expertise in one of the aforementioned areas, or any opening for a mathematician
who is also a good programmer, please don&#x27;t hesitate to contact me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:me@xuanruiqi.com&quot;&gt;me@xuanruiqi.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;location&quot;&gt;Location&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I&#x27;m primarily looking for jobs located in Japan, and particularly in Tokyo. I am also open to fully remote jobs if
I can work from Japan. I am happy to work irregular hours to accommodate my colleagues in different time zones.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not averse to relocation, however, especially within APAC (Asia-Pacific), as long as work visa sponsorship is available.
If you believe that I might be a good fit for your job, please do contact me regardless of your position.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding positions requiring relocation to the United States: I would love to have a chat, but please understand that I have no work authorization
in the U.S. and is unlikely to obtain one due to the policies of the current administration. Also, due to visa issues, it is impossible for me to relocate to
Taiwan, unfortunately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
